Guide to the Crawford Theater Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Crawford Theater collection
1663-1992
MS 1387
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
468.52
(828 boxes, 3 folios)
The collection consists of playbills and programs, photographs in a variety of formats, engravings, posters, clippings, and other printed material which document the performing arts in the United States and throughout the world from the seventeenth through the twentieth centuries. Material relating to dramatic performance forms the nucleus of the collection, but dance, opera, motion picture, circus, radio, and television performances are also represented.
Crawford, Jack Randall, 1878-
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, Series III boxes 301 to 304 and 306A to 306F (Posters, 1850-1980) are restricted due to their very fragile condition.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Jack Randall Crawford, 1930, and others, 1930-1995, 1997. Separated from the Underhill Moore Papers, 2006; and transfer from the Historical Sound Collection, 1996.
Related Material
Related material: Jack Randall Crawford Papers, MS 153, Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Related material: Theater Manuscripts Collection, MS 667, Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Related material: Crawford Theater Collection, Yale Drama Library, Yale University.
Scope and Contents
In December 1918, Jack Crawford, professor of English at Yale University, donated to the Yale University Library his collection of theater-related programs, playbills and printed and pictorial material. Until his retirement in 1946, Jack Crawford developed, maintained and publicized the collection. His involvement in the theater community of New Haven (he and his wife founded the first Little Theater in New Haven in 1921) and in the academic community provided him with opportunitites to advertise his collection and solicit donations of performing arts memorabilia. Originally housed in a small room in the old University Library, the collection was moved in 1930 to a specially designed room in the new Sterling Memorial Library. The collection expanded rapidly over the years, and was moved several times within the Library to accommodate its growth. In 1984, the collection was moved to Manuscripts and Archives.
The Crawford Theater Collection consists of playbills and programs, photographs in a variety of formats, engravings, posters, clippings and other printed material which document the performing arts in the United States and throughout the world from the seventeenth through the twentieth centuries. Material relating to dramatic performance forms the nucleus of the collection, but dance, opera, motion picture, circus, radio and television performances are also represented.
The Crawford Theater Collection consists of approximately 500 linear feet of material and is arranged in the following six series:
I. PLAYBILLS AND PROGRAMS, 1663-1989
II. PICTORIAL MATERIAL, 1800-1980
III. POSTERS, 1850-1980
IV. CLIPPINGS, 1800-1980
V. MISCELLANEA, 1850-1980
VI. PRINTED MATERIAL, 1900-1980
SERIES I, PLAYBILLS AND PROGRAMS, 1663-1989, consists of programs and playbills documenting theater, musical theater, variety, vaudeville, dance, motion picture, circus, and opera productions. While material from the British Isles (England, Scotland, Wales, and Ireland) and the United States is most prominant, the series contains programs and playbills from throughout the world. Dominating the series are programs which document performances in the major theaters of London, Boston, New Haven, New York and Philadelphia. Amateur, avant-garde, and college and university productions are represented to a lesser degree. The majority of programs are complete; however, many productions are represented by clipped cast lists only. Fewer then twenty early playbills are in the form of reproductions. Theater and music performances at Yale University are documented in the series. Additional programs for the Yale Dramatic Association productions may be found in the Association's records within the Yale University Archives record group 40-A-33. Programs mounted in scrapbooks are listed under Series IV, Clippings.
Due to their age, size, and type, the playbills and programs have been arranged in seven subseries, A through G. Subseries descriptions immediately precede the box listing for each subseries, and must be read to fully understand the distinctions between subseries. Basically, the division of subseries A through D is based on size, and the division of subseries E through G is based on type. One may need to review several subseries in order to find playbills and programs for any one production or for all holdings from a particular city or theater. The general descriptions of the subseries are as follows:
Subseries A:
Inclusive dates: 1795-1969
Largest dimension: between 18" and 36"
Type of container: "bully" box
Number of boxes: 19
Subseries B:
Inclusive dates: 1663-1860
Largest dimension: 17"
Type of container: flat grey box
Number of boxes: 11
Subseries C:
Inclusive dates: 1861-1971
Largest dimension: between 13" and 17"
Type of container: flat grey box
Number of boxes: 27
Subseries D:
Inclusive dates: 1861-1989
Largest dimension: 12"
Type of container: document case
Number of boxes: 461
Subseries E:
Bound playbills and programs
Inclusive dates: 1790-1950
Largest dimension: 19"
Type of container: variety
Number of boxes: 30
Subseries F:
Fabric playbills and programs
Inclusive dates: 1872-1923
Largest dimension: 20"
Type of container: flat grey box
Number of boxes: 1
Subseries G:
Film programs
Inclusive dates: 1913-1974
Largest dimension: 12"
Type of containers: document case
Number of boxes: 5
SERIES II, PICTORIAL MATERIAL, 1800-1980, consists of pictographic material, including tintypes, cartes-des-visites, cabinet photographs, glossy prints, lantern slides, newspaper and journal clippings, and engravings. The series is arranged in three sections: Actors and actresses, Motion picture stills, and Other materials.
Actors and actresses consists of photographic material arranged in several sub-sections. Pictorial images and photographs of many major theatrical figures are contained in this section, which includes select files on such nineteenth century American theater performers as Sarah Bernhardt, Jane Cowl, Eleanor Duse, and Edwin Booth.
Additional pictorial materials are arranged in topical sub-sections such as: Musical comedy, Burlesque, and Circus stars. Other sub-sections contain specific types of material including: Portraits, Actors: large prints, and items identified as part of the Greishaber Collection.
Motion picture stills consists of glossy prints of scenes and from motion pictures made from ca. 1930-1960.
Other materials includes a variety of pictorial forms, including cartes-des-visites, cabinet photographs, lantern slides, and engravings which portray many famous and lesser-known theatrical performers and entertainers in other fields.
SERIES III, POSTERS, 1850-1980, consists of several hundred American posters depicting theatrical productions, announcing theatrical performances, or promoting theatrical performers.
SERIES IV, CLIPPINGS, 1800-1980, consists of newspaper and journal clippings relating to performers, productions, and other aspects of the performing arts. This series is arranged in fourteen sections:
Actors and actresses
Actors: foreign
Actors: Shakespearean
Actors: Musical comedy
Actors: Motion pictures
Dancers
Circus performers
Dramatists
Theaters
Stock Companies, autographs, miscellanea
Critiques
Miscellanea
Scrapbooks
Actors and actresses consists of an alphabetical arrangement of clippings for theatrical and other performers (ca. 1800-1980). Clippings include pictorial views and informational items on many performers.
Critiques contains newspaper clippings of commentaries on theatrical and motion picture productions and related topics (ca. 1930-1960). These files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Scrapbooks contains several volumes of clippings, programs, and related materials collected by individuals active or interested in the world of professional theater.
SERIES V, MISCELLANEA, 1850-1980, contains printed material, clippings, pictorial material, paraphernalia, and miscellanea relating to several general topics on the theater and performing arts, as well as material acquired through individual accessions, or relating to specific individuals or theatrical organizations. Partial indices to portions of the Crawford Collection, including Boston theater programs from 1838-1929, are arranged in this series.
SERIES VI, THEATER PRINTED MATERIAL, 1900-1980, contains a variety of journals, magazines, and other publications devoted to the history and development of the performing arts.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series and two additions: I. Playbills and Programs, 1663-1989. II. Pictorial Material, 1800-1980. III. Posters, 1850-1980. IV. Clippings, 1800-1980. V. Miscellanea, 1850-1980. VI. Printed Material, 1900-1980.
Actors; Actresses; Ballet dancing; Burlesque (Theater); Circus performers; Circus -- United States; Mime; Minstrel shows; Minstrels; Motion picture actors and actresses -- United States; Motion picture programs -- United States; Musicals; Opera; Theater programs; Theater -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Theater -- France -- Paris; Theater -- Great Britain; Theater -- Ireland; Theater -- Massachusetts -- Boston; Theater -- New York (State) -- New York; Theater -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia; Theater -- United States; Theaters -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Theaters -- England -- London; Theaters -- Massachusetts -- Boston; Theaters -- New York (State) -- New York; Theaters -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia; Theaters; Theatrical paraphernalia; Theatrical posters, American; Playbills; Adams, Maude, 1872-1953; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor), 1810-1891; Barrymore, Ethel, 1879-1959; Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923; Booth, Edwin, 1833-1893; Booth, John Wilkes, 1838-1865; Booth, Junius Brutus, 1796-1852; Cornell, Katharine, 1893-1974; Cowl, Jane, 1884-1950; Crawford, Jack Randall, 1878-; Drew, John, 1853-1927; Duse, Eleonora, 1858-1924; Elliott, Maxine, 1868-1940; Fiske, Minnie Maddern, 1865-1932; Forrest, Edwin, 1806-1872; Garrick, David, 1717-1779; Hackett, James Henry, 1800-1871; Hallam, Lewis, 1740-1808; Hampden, Walter, 1879-1955; Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993; Hull, Josephine, 1877-1957; Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905; Kean, Edmund, 1787-1833; Kemble, Fanny, 1809-1893; Lenihan, Winifred, -1964; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865; Macready, William Charles, 1793-1873; Marlowe, Julia, 1865-1950; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Southern, E.A.; Wallack, James William, 1795-1864; Wallack, James William; Harland, Julia, active 19th century; Wallack, Lester, 1820-1888; Wignell, Thomas, 1753-1803
- Playbills and Programs, 1663-1989; Series I
  - Subseries A:, 1795-1969; Series I; 3 linear feet (19 boxes) Largest dimension: between 18" and 36"
    Scope and Contents
    The material within this subseries is arranged alphabetically first by country, then by city, then by theater, and then by year under the broader headings of the British Isles, the United States, and Other nations. Material documenting performances in cities and theaters not listed may be found in the miscellaneous and unidentified files which follow the material for a particular country or city.
    - British Isles
      - England
        - Bath, 1851, 1871-1876 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Birmingham, 1812-1866, undated, 1835-1862, 1825-1865 (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
        - Bristol, 1870-1877 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
        - Hull, 1820, 1833-1834 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Leeds, 1824, 1840-1843, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Liverpool, 1836-1853 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - London
          - Adelphi, 1819-1893 (Box 2, Folder 9)
          - Astley's, 1839-1865 (Box 2, Folder 10)
          - Bower Saloon, 1849, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 10)
          - Britannia, 1868, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 10)
          - Covent Garden, 1823-1894 (Box 2, Folder 11)
          - Drury Lane, 1817-1874, 1821-1875, 1852-1867 (Box 3, Folder 12-14)
          - East London, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 15)
          - English Opera House, 1820-1841 (Box 3, Folder 16)
          - Globe, 1869-1870 (Box 3, Folder 17)
          - Grecian, 1851-1880 (Box 3, Folder 18)
          - Haymarket, 1799, 1837-1874 (Box 3, Folder 19)
          - Haymarket, 1841-1844, 1841-1873 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
          - Her Majesty's, 1864 (Box 4, Folder 22)
          - Holborn, 1867-1873 (Box 4, Folder 23)
          - Lyceum, 1844-1874 (Box 4, Folder 24)
          - Olympic, 1835-1871 (Box 4, Folder 25)
          - Pavilion, 1860, 1886 (Box 5, Folder 26)
          - Prince of Wales, 1866-1880 (Box 5, Folder 27)
          - Princess's, 1843-1851, 1866, 1852-1872 (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
          - Queen's, 1835-1870 (Box 5, Folder 30)
          - Royalty, 1822, 1864-1870 (Box 5, Folder 31)
          - Sadler's Wells, 1832-1859 (Box 5, Folder 32)
          - Sadler's Wells, 1849-1862 (Box 6, Folder 33-34)
          - Saint James's, 1795, 1838-1893 (Box 6, Folder 35)
          - Sanger's, 1870 (Box 6, Folder 36)
          - Standard, 1847-1856, 1880 (Box 6, Folder 37)
          - Strand, 1837-1869 (Box 6, Folder 38)
          - Surrey, 1836-1872 (Box 6, Folder 39)
          - Vauxhall Gardens, 1828-1850 (Box 7, Folder 40)
          - Victoria, 1834-1868 (Box 7, Folder 41)
          - Miscellaneous London theatres (C - W), 1837-1911 (Box 7, Folder 42)
        - Manchester, 1847-1859 (Box 7, Folder 43)
        - Miscellaneous English cities (B - T), 1796-1905 (Box 7, Folder 44)
        - Unidentified England, 1857, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 44)
      - Ireland
        - Dublin
          - Queen's, 1845-1869 (Box 8, Folder 45)
          - Rotunda/Rotundo, 1839-1874 (Box 8, Folder 46)
          - Theatre Royal, 1809-1853, 1856-1870, 1852-1871, 1835-1870 (Box 8, Folder 47-50)
          - Theatre Royal, Abbey Street, 1829-1841 (Box 9, Folder 51)
          - Miscellaneous Dublin theatres (A - R), 1799-1880 (Box 9, Folder 52)
      - Scotland
        - Edinburgh
          - Adelphi, 1836-1850 (Box 9, Folder 53)
          - Caledonian, 1828 (Box 9, Folder 53)
          - Dale's Rooms, 1817 (Box 9, Folder 53)
          - Edinburgh Theatre, 1876-1877 (Box 9, Folder 53)
          - Marsh's Royal Lyceum, 1862 (Box 9, Folder 54)
          - Prince of Wales's Operetta House, 1863 (Box 9, Folder 54)
          - Princess's, 1875-1878 (Box 9, Folder 54)
          - Queen's Theatre and Opera House, 1858-1862, 1868, 1875 (Box 9, Folder 54)
          - Royal Amphitheatre, 1828 (Box 9, Folder 54)
          - Theatre Royal, 1843-1849, 1874-1878 (Box 9, Folder 55)
          - Unidentified Edinburgh theatres, 1829 (Box 9, Folder 55)
        - Glasgow, 1830, 1843-1844, 1856-1857, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 56)
        - Unidentified Scotland, 1908 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - United States
      - Boston
        - Academy of Music, 1861-1862 (Box 10, Folder 57)
        - Boston Museum, 1843-1850, 1850-1879 (Box 10, Folder 58-59)
        - Boston Theatre, 1847-1880, 1885, undated (Box 10, Folder 60)
        - Howard Athenaeum, 1851-1886, undated (Box 10, Folder 61)
        - National, 1849-1860, undated (Box 10, Folder 62)
        - Miscellaneous Boston theatres (A - W), 1854-1883, undated (Box 10, Folder 63)
      - New Haven
        - Brewster Hall, 1858-1865 (Box 11, Folder 64)
        - Exchange Hall, 1852, 1860, undated (Box 11, Folder 64)
        - Little Theatre Guild, 1924, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 64)
        - Music Hall, 1861-1876, undated (Box 11, Folder 65)
        - Miscellaneous New Haven theatres (B - Y), 1830-1916 (Box 11, Folder 66)
        - Unidentified New Haven, undated (Box 11, Folder 66)
      - New York
        - Academy of Music, 1862-1898 (Box 11, Folder 67)
        - American, 1833-1836, 1864, undated (Box 11, Folder 67)
        - Barnum's Museum, 1851-1862, undated (Box 11, Folder 68)
        - Booth's, 1869, 1881 (Box 11, Folder 68)
        - Bowery, 1829-1866 (Box 11, Folder 69)
        - Broadway, 1852-1866, 1888 (Box 12, Folder 70)
        - Burton's, 1849-1856 (Box 12, Folder 70)
        - Fifth Avenue, 1869-1898 (Box 12, Folder 71)
        - Globe Museum, 1895-1898 (Box 12, Folder 71)
        - Globe Theatre, 1870-1876, undated (Box 12, Folder 71)
        - Grand Opera House, 1869-1880 (Box 12, Folder 71)
        - Metropolitan, 1873-1874, undated (Box 12, Folder 72)
        - National, 1840, 1853 (Box 12, Folder 72)
        - Niblo's Garden, 1852-1864, 1863-1882 (Box 12, Folder 73-74)
        - Olympic, 1841-1877, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 75)
        - Park, 1805-1833, undated (Box 12, Folder 75)
        - Theatre Comique, 1868-1879 (Box 13, Folder 76)
        - Wallack's, 1852-1879 (Box 13, Folder 77)
        - Winter Garden, 1860-1864 (Box 13, Folder 78)
        - Wood's Museum, 1871-1874 (Box 13, Folder 78)
        - Miscellaneous New York theatres
          - A - B, 1851-1899, undated (Box 13, Folder 79)
          - C - G, 1851-1933, undated (Box 13, Folder 80)
          - H - L, 1795-1913, undated (Box 13, Folder 81)
          - M - W; unidentified, 1843-1969, undated (Box 13, Folder 82)
      - Philadelphia
        - American Academy of Music, 1859-1862, 1867 (Box 14, Folder 83)
        - Arch Street, 1851-1871, 1832, 1848 (Box 14, Folder 84-85)
        - Chestnut Street, 1828-1849 (Box 14, Folder 86-88)
        - Chestnut Street, 1849-1867, 1835-1845 (Box 15, Folder 89-93)
        - Walnut Street, 1829-1871, 1877, undated (Box 16, Folder 94-98)
        - Miscellaneous Philadelphia theatres
          - C-M, 1858-1861, undated (Box 16, Folder 99)
          - N-W; unidentified, 1818-1933, undated (Box 16, Folder 100)
    - Other U. S. cities
      - Baltimore
        - Baltimore Theatre, 1814, 1824-1834 (Box 17, Folder 101)
        - Front Street, 1833, 1846, 1854, 1863-1865 (Box 17, Folder 101)
        - Holliday Street, 1831, 1851-1853, 1871 (Box 17, Folder 101)
      - Chicago, 1862, 1869, 1904, undated (Box 17, Folder 102)
      - Cincinnati
        - Cincinnati Theatre, 1832, 1844 (Box 17, Folder 103)
        - National, 1837, 1847, 1872, undated (Box 17, Folder 103)
        - Pike's Opera House, undated (Box 17, Folder 103)
        - Wood's, 1865-1869 (Box 17, Folder 103)
      - Mobile, 1835, 1847, 1870 (Box 17, Folder 104)
      - New Orleans
        - Academy of Music, 1865-1882 (Box 17, Folder 105)
        - Acquidneck Hall, 1862 (Box 17, Folder 105)
        - American, 1843 (Box 17, Folder 105)
        - Saint Charles, 1837-1852, 1868-1870 (Box 17, Folder 106)
        - Varieties, 1868-1870 (Box 17, Folder 106)
        - Unidentified, 1869, undated (Box 17, Folder 106)
      - Providence, 1804, 1872 (Box 17, Folder 107)
      - Saint Louis
        - DeBar's Opera House, 1872-1875 (Box 17, Folder 108)
        - Olympic, 1868, 1876 (Box 17, Folder 108)
        - Saint Louis Theatre, 1835, 1847-1848 (Box 17, Folder 108)
      - San Francisco, 1852, 1863, 1877, 1887-1889 (Box 18, Folder 109)
      - Vicksburg, 1838-1839 May (Box 18, Folder 110-111)
      - Washington, DC
        - Columbia, 1905 (Box 18, Folder 112)
        - Ford's, 1864-1865 (Box 18, Folder 112)
        - National, 1854, 1871 (Box 18, Folder 112)
        - Washington Theatre, 1813-1827 (Box 18, Folder 112)
        - Unidentified, 1832 (Box 18, Folder 112)
      - Miscellaneous U. S. cities
        - A - I, 1816-1938, undated (Box 18, Folder 113)
        - J - R, 1827-1922, undated (Box 19, Folder 114)
        - S - W, 1834-1923, undated (Box 19, Folder 115)
        - Unidentified, 1857-1861, 1865-1875, 1888, 1923, undated (Box 19, Folder 115)
    - Other nations
      - Australia, 1873, undated (Box 19, Folder 116)
      - Austria, 1902, 1925, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 116)
      - Bolivia, 1911 (Box 19, Folder 116)
      - Canada, 1862, 1869, 1873, undated (Box 19, Folder 117)
      - China, undated (Box 19, Folder 117)
      - Cuba, 1877, 1902-1903, 1916, 1924, undated (Box 19, Folder 117)
      - Czechoslovakia, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 117)
      - France, 1867, 1892-1894, 1923, undated (Box 19, Folder 118)
      - Germany, 1895-1898, 1911, 1928, undated (Box 19, Folder 118)
      - Hungary, 1896 (Box 19, Folder 118)
      - Jamaica, 1875, 1889, undated (Box 19, Folder 118)
      - Martinique, 1894 (Box 19, Folder 119)
      - Mexico, 1935, undated (Box 19, Folder 119)
      - Norway, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 119)
      - Spain, 1884 (Box 19, Folder 119)
      - Surinam, 1895 (Box 19, Folder 119)
      - U.S.S.R., undated (Box 19, Folder 119)
      - Unidentified, 1870, 1890-1896, 1907, undated (Box 19, Folder 119)
  - Subseries B:, 1663-1860; Series I; 2.75 linear feet (11 boxes) Largest dimension: 17"
    The material within this subseries is arranged alphabetically first by country, then by city, then by theater, and then by year under the broader headings of the British Isles, the United States, and Other nations. Fewer than twenty early playbills are in the form of reproductions. Material documenting performances in cities and theaters not listed may be found in the miscellaneous and unidentified files which follow the material for a particular country or city.
    - British Isles
      - England
        - Barnwell, 1829 (Box 20, Folder 120)
        - Bath, 1788-1792, 1808, 1815, 1819-1820, 1845 (Box 20, Folder 121)
        - Birmingham, 1796-1842 (Box 20, Folder 122-126)
        - Brighton, 1804 (Box 20, Folder 127)
        - Bristol, 1782, 1790-1792, 1809, 1815, 1842, 1847 (Box 20, Folder 128)
        - Buxton, 1796 (Box 20, Folder 129)
        - Cambridge, 1786 (Box 20, Folder 130)
        - Cheltenham, 1781, 1803, 1838 (Box 20, Folder 131)
        - Durham, 1812-1814 (Box 20, Folder 132)
        - Hull, 1798, 1820-1824, 1831, 1844 (Box 20, Folder 133)
        - Leeds, 1801, 1817-1828 (Box 20, Folder 134-136)
        - Leeds, 1829, 1840-1843 (Box 20, Folder 137)
        - Leicester, 1802 (Box 21, Folder 138)
        - Liverpool, 1796-1797, 1803-1810, 1816-1820, 1827, 1832-1835 (Box 21, Folder 139-141)
        - London
          - Adelphi, 1819-1822, 1828-1839, 1845, 1851-1860 (Box 21, Folder 142)
          - Astley's, 1826, 1833, 1845 (Box 21, Folder 143)
          - Covent Garden, 1754-1755, 1775-1777, 1782-1786, 1785-1788 May, 1785 September-1789 (Box 21, Folder 144-149)
          - Covent Garden, 1790-1802 (Box 22, Folder 150-152)
          - Covent Garden, 1804-1840, 1848 (Box 22, Folder 153-159)
          - Drury Lane, 1663, 1696, 1756-1760, 1765, 1773-1778, 1783-1808, 1813-1822 (Box 23, Folder 160-168)
          - Drury Lane, 1823-1827 January-March (Box 24, Folder 169-171)
          - Drury Lane, 1827 April-Jun, 1827 October-Dec, 1828, 1829 February-Jun, 1829 October (Box 24, Folder 172-177)
          - Drury Lane, 1829 November-1830 May (Box 25, Folder 178-184)
          - Drury Lane, 1830 Jun, 1830 October-Dec, 1831-1832, 1833 January-May 14, 1833 May23-Dec, 1834-1835, 1836 February-Dec, 1837-1843, 1852, undated (Box 26, Folder 185-194)
          - East London, 1817-1820 (Box 26, Folder 195)
          - English Opera House, 1815-1836 (Box 26, Folder 196-197)
          - Haymarket, 1766, 1780, 1784, 1793, 1808, undated, 1825-1833, 1850-1860 (Box 26, Folder 198-199)
          - Lyceum, 1809-1815, 1849, 1850 (Box 27, Folder 200)
          - Olympic, 1827-1833, 1844, 1848, 1852 (Box 27, Folder 201)
          - Princess, 1846, 1854-1856 (Box 27, Folder 202)
          - Royal Coburg, 1818-1831 (Box 27, Folder 203)
          - Sadler's Wells, 1825, 1830-1832, 1859 (Box 27, Folder 204)
          - Strand, 1816-1818, 1851, 1857 (Box 27, Folder 205)
          - Surrey, 1811, 1816-1818, 1823-1843, 1849 (Box 27, Folder 206)
          - Theatre in Goodman's Fields, 1741 (Box 27, Folder 207)